{"tossups": [{"question": "In his concurrence to this Supreme Court case, Justice Goldberg listed his belief in an \u201cabsolute, unconditional privilege\u201d around a certain issue. The majority opinion in this case notes an approximate cost of $4800 for an advertisement that was accompanied by a letter from Asa Philip Randolph. A commissioner from Montgomery, Alabama brought forth this case, which established a standard for falsity known as \u201creckless disregard.\u201d The notion of \u201cactual malice\u201d was central to, for ten points, what Supreme Court case dealing with a major newspaper from a Mid-Atlantic state?", "answer": "<em><b><u>New York Times</u></b> Co. v. Sullivan</em> (prompt on \u201cSullivan\u201d; accept <em>The</em> <em><b><u>New York</u></b></em> <em><b><u>Times</u></b> Company v. L. B. Sullivan</em>; accept <em><b><u>NYT</u></b> v. Sullivan</em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This thinker outlined a theory in which three or more options ranked by preference can lead to intransitive results. Thomas Malthus\u2019s population studies were partly inspired by this thinker\u2019s notion of the \u201cperfectibility of society\u201d through progress in the sciences. This mathematician found that, when the probability of a correct outcome per juror was over 50 percent, adding jurors was optimal in a namesake \"jury theorem.\" For ten points, name this Enlightenment thinker, and namesake of an election method, who died in prison during the French Revolution.", "answer": "Marquis de <b><u>Condorcet</u></b> (or Marie Jean Antoine Nicolas de <b><u>Caritat</u></b>; accept Nicolas de <b><u>Condorcet</u></b>; accept <b><u>Condorcet</u></b>'s Jury Theorem; accept <b><u>Condorcet</u></b> Method))", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {"question": "The Namal Institute was founded by this politician, who previously was chancellor of the University of Bradford. This politician admitted to ball tampering while a member of a team that won the 1992 World Cup in the sport he played professionally. The Khyber Pakhtunwa formed a coalition with the government of this former cricketer who publicly stated his intention to restore the policies of Muhammad Ali Jinnah. For ten points, name this politician, the first Pakistani prime minister to be ousted through a vote of no-confidence in 2022.", "answer": "Imran <b><u>Khan</u></b> (or Imran Ahmed <b><u>Khan</u></b> Niazi)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "A <em>qibla</em> [[KEE-blah]], reminiscent of one in Cordoba, can be found in this city\u2019s Kutubiyyah Mosque. The El Badi Palace can be found in this city, once led by Thami El Glaoui. A set of seven patron saints are venerated in this popular pilgrimage site for Sufis. The Menara Gardens in this city were designed under Caliph Abd al-Mu\u2019min, and the walls of this city were built under the orders of Ali ibn Yusuf, the fifth emir of the Almoravids. The African capital of the Almohad Empire was, for ten points, what \"Imperial City\" of Morocco.", "answer": "<b><u>Marrakech</u></b> (or <b><u>Marrakesh</u></b>; accept A<b><u>marakus</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In this election year, the failure of one vice presidential candidate to receive enough votes led to a contingent election in which Richard Granger was defeated. Hugh Lawson White was among the four candidates from the Whig Party who ran in this year in which Daniel Webster was also a nominee. The winning vice presidential candidate in this election year claimed to have personally killed Tecumseh. Richard Mentor Johnson ran alongside the winner in this election year who was born in the Dutch region of Kinderhook, New York. For ten points, name this election year, a victory for Martin van Buren.", "answer": "United States Presidential Election of <b><u>1836</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A thirty-five year study by this scientist was inspired by a sample of crystalline insulin provided by Robert Robinson. Along with Barbara Low, this scientist discovered that the structure of penicillin contained the B-lactam ring. The first structure of a steroid, cholesteryl iodide, was discovered by C.H. Carlisle and this scientist. In 1964, this woman won the Nobel Prize in Chemistry for discovering the structure of vitamin B12. For ten points, which British chemist pioneered the use of X-Ray crystallography to determine the structures of biomolecules?", "answer": "Dorothy <b><u>Hodgkin</u></b> (or Dorothy Mary <b><u>Crowfoot</u></b>; or Dorothy Mary <b><u>Hodgkin</u></b>)", "metadata": "Science - Chemistry"}, {"question": "This deity's cult center at Lagina, in the Anatolian region of Caria, was confused for a cult of Diana by Tacitus in a mistaken interpretation of the nickname \"Trivia.\" The Deipnon [[DEEP-nohn]] offering, in which a meal was served on an altar once a lunar month, honored this goddess. The <em>kleidos agoge</em> [[KLAY-dohss ah-GOH-geh]] was a ritual performed at festivals honoring this deity, involving a young girl carrying a key on a road leading to the city <em>Stratonikea</em> [[strah-toh-nee-KEH-ah]]. Regarded as a protector of homes, for ten points, who was this Greek goddess of magic?", "answer": "<b><u>Hecate</u></b> [[HEH-kah-teh]] (or <b><u>Hekate</u></b>; accept phonetic pronunciations)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "The Lorenzen Group fought against this movement, which included members of the Churchill Club. This movement opposed a government that referred to its central country as \u201cthe Cream Front\u201d due to the abundance of dairy products there. BOPA and Holger were among the groups that made up this movement, described in Lois Lowry\u2019s book <em>Number the</em> <em>Stars</em>. Christian X [[the tenth]] was seen as a symbol of this movement, perhaps due to his short reply to a telegram sent by Hitler. For ten points, name this insurgent movement against the Nazis in cities like Copenhagen.", "answer": "<b><u>Danish Resistance</u></b> (accept Den <b><u>danske modstandsbev\u00e6gelse</u></b>; accept descriptive answers indicating resistance against Germany or the Nazis in <b><u>Denmark</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Ustad Mansur was a court artist during this empire and was the earliest to depict the dodo bird in color. The Persian artist Abd al-Samad was commissioned by a leader of this empire to paint miniatures for books such as the <em>Tutinama</em>. Rulers of this empire commissioned the Shalimar Gardens and brought in leading architects to design the city of Fatehpur Sikri. A ruler of this empire commissioned a marble mausoleum for his wife, Mumtaz. For ten points, name this empire, during which the Taj Mahal was commissioned by Shah Jahan.", "answer": "<b><u>Mughal</u></b> Empire (accept <b><u>Mogul</u></b> Empire)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The wife of Abu Lahab was said to have once spitefully thrown these objects in Muhammad\u2019s path. In a treatise, John Calvin claimed that five of these objects were in Bourges [[BOORZH]] and an unknown amount were in Sienna. Among the instruments of the Passion was an object made of these materials, which, upon its placement, was accompanied by a group exclaiming, \u201cHail, King of the Jews!\" A relic made of these objects was allegedly used during the Crucifixion to mockingly crown Jesus. For ten points, name these sharp objects, which, according to a Greek proverb and the glam metal band Poison, every rose has.", "answer": "<b><u>Thorn</u></b>s (accept Crown of <b><u>Thorn</u></b>s)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "With Michel Ange Bernard Mangourit, this man organized an expedition led by former members of the Pulaski Legion to conquer Spanish Florida. This son-in-law of vice president George Clinton was forced to seek asylum after the Montagnards [[mohn-tahn-YAHRDS]] seized power and ousted him. Arriving on the <em>Embuscade</em> [[ehm-boo-SKAHD]], this diplomat's mission to the U.S. led to a 1793 attempt to recruit American privateers to fight the British during the Napoleonic Wars. For ten points, name this diplomat and \"Citizen\" who sparked a mild controversy in the early American Republic.", "answer": "Edmond-Charles <b><u>Gen\u00eat</u></b> [[zheh-NEH]] (or Citizen <b><u>Gen\u00eat</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A leader of this country tried to organize a party to compete with a neighboring country\u2019s People\u2019s Action Party and came to be given the title \u201cFather of Independence\u201d or \u201cBapa Kemerdekaan.\" Tunku Abdul Rahman was a founding father of this country, which fought against Britain during a 1948 to 1960 conflict. \"New Villages\" were concentration camps built during an \"Emergency\" in this present-day country. For ten points, name this Southeast Asian country that faced a major communist insurgency in its state of Sarawak.", "answer": "<b><u>Malaysia</u></b> (prompt on \"Malaya\" or \"British Malaya\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A document confirming this event replaced one letter of its central figure\u2019s name with a \u201cV\u201d and was found in Ostrow. Snowy Evans and Cedric Popkin were involved in this event, the central figure of which was followed by Wop May prior to it. After passing Morlancourt Ridge, close to the Somme, this event's central figure was engaged by a Sopwith Camel before being forced to land his Fokker. Occurring after its central figure allegedly said \u201ckaput,\" for ten points, what was this event in which a German flying ace was shot down?", "answer": "<b><u>Death</u></b> of the <b><u>Red Baron</u></b> (accept <b><u>Death</u></b> of Baron Manfred Albrecht Freiherr von <b><u>Richthofen</u></b>; accept clear-knowledge equivalents in place of \u201cdeath\u201d, like \u201ckilling\u201d; prompt on answers that only involve a plane being downed)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "One man with this surname started a magazine originally known as <em>One Man\u2019s</em> <em>Opinion</em>. Another man with this surname challenged Roy Cohn to produce a list of 130 names \"before sundown.\" William F. Buckley insisted an organization founded by a man with this surname should be ousted to the fringes of conservatism. After Joseph McCarthy publicly named Fred Fisher, a lawyer with this surname asked him, \"Have you no sense of decency?\" For ten points, give this surname of lawyer Joseph N. and the right-wing founder of the John Birch Society, Robert.", "answer": "<b><u>Welch</u></b> (accept Robert Henry Winborne <b><u>Welch</u></b> [Jr.]; or Joseph Nye <b><u>Welch</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One leader of this empire defeated a 30,000-man force that was double the size of his own army at the Battle of the Achelous [[ah-KEH-lohss]] River. One leader of this empire converted a defeated rival\u2019s skull into a drinking cup, and a man known as \u201cthe Logothete\u201d was defeated by this empire at the Battle of Pliska. Khan Krum was a ruler of this empire, which faced a campaign waged by Emperor Nikephoros [[nee-keh-FOH-rohss]] I. Simeon I was a ruler of this empire who oversaw its expansion into Hungary and Serbia. For ten points, the Byzantines often fought with what Balkan empire?", "answer": "<b><u>Bulgar</u></b>ian Empire (or First <b><u>Bulgar</u></b>ian Empire; accept Tsardom of <b><u>Bulgaria</u></b> but do not reveal it as an answer; accept <b><u>Balgar</u></b>ysko Tsesarystviye)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The first volume of a work by this man was accidentally burned by a maid employed by John Stuart Mill, forcing this man to rewrite it entirely. The lines \u201che is epic\u201d were used by this man to praise Oliver Cromwell in a work that exemplifies his belief that a certain group were \u201cthe modellers [and] creators of whatsoever the general mass...contrived to do.\u201d The concept of the \u201cGreat Man\u201d in history was outlined by this theorist, who wrote a three-volume history of an event beginning in 1789. For ten points, name this Scottish historian who wrote <em>The French Revolution: A History</em>.", "answer": "Thomas <b><u>Carlyle</u></b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "During this prime minister\u2019s tenure, a group of businessmen who opposed one effort formed the Citizens\u2019 Committee of One Thousand. The need for funding industrial research led this prime minister\u2019s government to establish the NRC. More than 30,000 workers organized a general strike in Winnipeg during the tenure of this man, who was opposed by Henri Bourassa. The Conscription Crisis affected the tenure of this prime minister whose government passed the War Measures Act in 1914. For ten points, name this prime minister who led Canada during World War One.", "answer": "Robert <b><u>Borden</u></b> (or Sir Robert Laird <b><u>Borden</u></b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "Karen Wilkin claimed that this painting depicted \u201cthe bungling malfeasance\u201d of one government. The British cession of Senegal was the intended goal of the central group depicted in this painting while en route to Port Louis. Fifteen members of the central group in this painting died, with survivors resorting to cannibalism. After drifting a hundred miles off course, the namesake ship from this painting ran aground off the coast of Mauritania. Also known as <em>Shipwreck Scene</em>, for ten points, what is this historical painting by Theodore Gericault [[zheh-ree-KOH]]?", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>Raft of the Medusa</u></b></em> (or Le <b><u>Radeau de la Meduse</u></b>; accept <b><u>Scene de Naufrage</u> </b>or <b><u>Shipwreck Scene</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Defeating this ruler allowed the Roman general Lucullus [[loo-KULL-us]] to gain a legendary fortune. An attempt to partition the region of Paphlagonia [[pah-flah-GOH-nyah] with Nicomedes [[nik-oh-MEE-dees]] IV led to the first of this ruler\u2019s namesake wars. This leader\u2019s invasion of Greece was thwarted by the Roman general Sulla at the 86 BCE Battle of Chaeronea [[kay-ROH-neh-uh]]. This man's soldiers allegedly killed 80,000 Roman settlers in the Asiatic Vespers. For ten points, name this king of Pontus who lost three namesake wars to Rome.", "answer": "<b><u>Mithridates</u></b> VI of Pontus (accept <b><u>Mithradatic</u></b> Wars)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This city is the home of Karim Amir, who desperately tries to escape the southern section of this city in the autobiographical novel <em>The Buddha of Suburbia</em> by Hanif Kureishi. The experiences of Bangladeshi immigrants moving to this city in the late 1900s is recounted in Monica Ali's <em>Brick Lane</em>. This city is the capital of a country toward which a plane carrying Gibreel Farishta and Saladin Chamcha travels in a novel subject to a fatwa by Ayatollah Khomeini, <em>The Satanic Verses</em>. Many South Asian authors write about their experiences growing up in, for ten points, what European capital?", "answer": "<b><u>London</u></b>", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>While aboard the HMS</u> </b><em><b><u>Crowley</u></b></em><b><u>, this man organized attempts to weaken the</u></b> <b><u>Hanover militia by encouraging plantation slaves to revolt. The battle of Point</u></b> <b><u>Pleasant ended a conflict named for this noble which broke out after settlers aimed to</u></b> <b><u>hunt in Shawnee (+)</u> and Mingo territory. This man fled his post after his ally, the British Naval captain Robert Howe, shelled and burned the port of Norfolk to the ground after the Patriots (*) </b>captured it. For ten points, name this Royal Governor of Virginia who fled his post following the outbreak of the Revolutionary War.", "answer": "John <b><u>Murray</u></b>, Lord <b><u>Dunmore</u></b> (accept either underlined portion; accept Lord <b><u>Dunmore</u></b>'s War)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Historian T.S. Burns challenged Charles Oman's theory that this battle led to</u></b> <b><u>the rise of the medieval knight. Alatheus [[ah-lah-THEH-ooss]] assisted one leader</u></b> <b><u>during this battle, in which one side was bolstered by the Greutungs [[GROY-tungs]].</u></b> <b><u>Taking place near (+)</u> Edirne, in modern Turkey, this battle was a victory for Fritigern, a Tervingi chieftain, who took up arms against an emperor killed in action, (*) </b>Valens. For ten points, name this 378 victory for the Goths over the Roman Empire at a city named for one of \"Five Good Emperors.\"", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Adrianople</u></b> (accept Battle of <b><u>Hadrianopolis</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Jim Beaton prevented this person from being kidnapped by Ian Ball. This</u></b> <b><u>person won a gold medal at the 1971 European Eventing Championships and was</u></b> <b><u>voted that year's BBC Sports Personality of the Year. This person rode the horse</u></b> <b><u>Goodwill at the (+)</u> Montreal Olympics and became president of the British Olympic Association in 1983. This person was first married to Mark Phillips (*) </b>in a 1973 wedding with a television audience of 100 million viewers. For ten points, name this only daughter of Queen Elizabeth II.", "answer": "Princess <b><u>Anne</u></b> of Edinburgh (accept <b><u>Anne</u></b>, Princess Royal; or <b><u>Anne</u></b> Elizabeth Alice Louise; do not accept or prompt on \"Queen Anne\")", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b><u>The first generation of the</u> </b><em><b><u>mujahideen</u></b></em><b><u> accompanied this general in his</u></b> <b><u>campaign to root out apostasy during the Ridda Wars, which was led by tribal leader</u></b> <b><u>Musaylima. Under Umar, this general defeated a relief force at the Battle of Uqab Pass</u></b> <b><u>sent by (+)</u> Emperor Heraclius to relieve the besieged Byzantine garrison in Damascus. The unification of the Arabian (*) </b>peninsula was facilitated by the victories of, for ten points, what Rashidun general and \"Sword of God\" who won the Battle of Yarmouk?", "answer": "<b><u>Khalid</u></b> ibn al-<b><u>Walid</u></b> (accept either underlined portion; or <b><u>Khalid</u></b> ibn al-<b><u>Walid</u> </b>ibn al-Mughira al-Makhzumi; accept <b><u>Sayf Allah</u></b> or <b><u>Sword of God</u></b> before \"Sword\" is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Though made of brick, one of these buildings, built during the Song Dynasty, is</u></b> <b><u>named for its resemblance to rusted iron and can be found in Kaifeng. One of these</u></b> <b><u>buildings, named for the Wild Goose, was built during the Tang Dynasty, while the (+)</u></b> <b>Lingxiao type of these buildings was originally part of Tianning Monastery. Eaves were extended to separate the tiers of these buildings, a Korean example of which included text from the oldest sutra of the (*) </b>Mahayana sect. For ten points, name these towers often serving religious functions in Buddhism.", "answer": "<b><u>Pagoda</u></b>s (or <b><u>T\u01ce</u></b>; accept <b><u>Pagoda</u></b> of Fogong Temple; or Iron <b><u>Pagoda</u></b>; or Giant Wild Goose <b><u>Pagoda</u></b>; or D\u00e0y\u00e0n <b><u>t\u01ce</u></b>; or Lingxiao <b><u>Pagoda</u></b>)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "<b><u>William Johnson helped negotiate a treaty at this location in which the U.S.</u></b> <b><u>gained land in one state via the New Purchase. That treaty, signed at this place,</u></b> <b><u>involved the sale of 127,000 acres of land to George Croghan [[KROH-an]], a fur</u></b> <b><u>trader from the Ohio (+)</u> Country. A 1784 treaty signed at this place dealt with land one side acquired during the Beaver Wars. A treaty aiming to update boundaries, following the Royal Proclamation of 1763, was signed at this place by one member of each of the Six (*) </b>Nations. For ten points, name this \"Fort\" in Rome, New York where two treaties were signed by the Iroquois Confederacy.", "answer": "Fort <b><u>Stanwix</u></b> (accept Treaty of Fort <b><u>Stanwix</u></b>; prompt on \u201cRome\u201d, New York)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In a novel by this man, a group known as \u201cthe Quality\u201d holds power, while a</u></b> <b><u>character whose power of \u201cconduction\u201d is an asset to a network of the Underground</u></b> <b><u>Railroad. This author of</u> </b><em><b><u>The Water Dancer</u></b></em><b><u> analyzed family (+)</u> structures in \u201cthe Age of Mass Incarceration\u201d and penned an essay that cites housing discrimination as one of a number of reasons for adopting the central (*) </b>policy. For ten points, name this African-American writer for the <em>Atlantic</em> who is an advocate of reparations.", "answer": "Ta-Nehisi <b><u>Coates</u></b> (or Ta-Nehisi Paul <b><u>Coates</u></b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {"question": "<b><u>This explorer\u2019s son of the same name led a failed rebellion against his killers</u></b> <b><u>and was nicknamed \"El Mozo,\" or \u201cthe Lad.\" Juan de Saavedra was sent on a</u></b> <b><u>reconnaissance mission by this explorer to modern Valparaiso, Chile. Nicknamed \"El</u></b> <b><u>Adelantado,\" (+)</u> this man was defeated by the brothers Hernando and Gonzalo at the Battle of Las Salinas. This man provided reinforcements after the Battle of Cajamarca to a man with whom he later entered into a dispute over control of (*) </b>Cuzco. For ten points, name this Spanish conquistador who fought the Inca with, and later opposed, Francisco Pizarro.", "answer": "Diego de <b><u>Almagro</u></b> I (prompt on \u201cEl Viejo\u201d; prompt on \u201cEl Adelantado\u201d before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The artist of this work took fourteen years to complete a full-size replica of it</u></b> <b><u>while in exile. Louis-L\u00e9opold Boilly [[bwah-YEE]] painted a work focusing on a public</u></b> <b><u>viewing of this painting, which features an Ottoman representative named Halet</u></b> <b><u>Efendi. (+)</u> The central figure\u2019s mother, Marie, is present in this painting and is notably given a prominent position. A gallery of onlookers in the background of this painting looks down on a scene in which Pope Pius VII faces a man lifting a golden (*) </b>crown toward his own head. Set in Notre-Dame de Paris, for ten points, what is this Jacques-Louis David painting?", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>Coronation of Napoleon</u></b></em> (or <em>Le</em> <em><b><u>Sacre de Napoleon</u></b></em>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>The pseudonym \u201cGrant Lloyd\u201d was used by a woman of this surname who</u></b> <b><u>served as the first Principal of Lady Margaret Hall and borrowed money to found St.</u></b> <b><u>Hughes College at Oxford. During its revolution, a man of this surname visited (+)</u></b> <b>France, where he fell in love with Annette Vallon [[vah-YOHN]]. During a walking tour through the Welsh Marches, that man was inspired to write a poem about a \u201cdear, dear Sister\u201d named Dorothy with this surname. That poem is set along the River (*) </b>Wye. For ten points, name this surname of the poet of \u201cTintern Abbey\u201d, William.", "answer": "<b><u>Wordsworth</u></b> (accept William <b><u>Wordsworth</u></b>)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "<b><u>Western artist Frederic Remington depicted this man in the landscape</u></b> <b><u>painting [this explorer]</u> </b><em><b><u>Heads out North</u></b></em><b><u>, showing him accompanied by native scouts.</u></b> <b><u>The \"Conquest of (+)</u> Cibola\" was undertaken by this man, whose expeditions led to the defeat of Zuni and other Pueblo people but found very few precious metals. The discovery of the legendary city of El (*) </b>Dorado was the goal of, for ten points, which <em>conquistador</em> who explored much of the Southwestern U.S. in the early 1540s?", "answer": "Francisco V\u00e1zquez de <b><u>Coronado</u></b> (or Francisco V\u00e1zquez de <b><u>Coronado</u></b> y Luj\u00e1n)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>Stephen Nye wrote a history of this movement, several of whose members</u></b> <b><u>gathered at the Feathers Tavern to draft a petition to Parliament seeking relief from</u></b> <b><u>following the Thirty-Nine Articles. (+)</u> Theophilus Lindsey organized meetings of these people at Essex Street Chapel, which were attended by men like the scientist Joseph Priestly. An 1813 Act granted tolerance to this movement, before which its renunciation of the Nicene (*) </b>Creed led it to be blasphemed. For ten points, name this Christian movement which rejects the Holy Trinity.", "answer": "<b><u>Unitarian</u></b>ism", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}